Kenny Bean

Computer Science Professional

Summary

Hardworking, creative computer science professional with internship experience of 1.5 years. Seeking to start an ambitious career within a company that will provide new experiences and the opportunity for advancement and exposure to cutting edge computing technology.

Employment

Working Student

September, 2016-Present

Autoliv-Nissin Brake Systems, Southfield, MI

- Created hardware in the loop (HIL) set ups.
- Ran multiple kinds of tests based on specifications given by engineers.
- Wrote data visualization/report generation software for the HIL in Matlab's App Designer.
- Worked in a CarSim and dSpace Environment.
- Modified the dSPACE environment to meet the specifications given by algorithm engineer.
- Created temperature and current gauge to prevent damage to the ECU on HIL bench during testing.

Server

June, 2014-December, 2016

Red Robin Gourmet Burgers, Madison Heights, MI

- Tended to the needs of guests.
- Completed additional tasks executed around the restaurant given to me by managers.
- Trusted with the negotiation of disgruntled guests.
- Received numerous good reviews/ comments about my service.

Education

- Bachelors in Science, 2014-2018, Software Engineering, University of Michigan-Dearborn, MI
 - **GPA:** 3.4
 - Preferred areas of study: Website Technologies and Artificial Intelligence
 - **UPE Honors Society Member**
- High School Diploma, 2010-2014, General Studies, Hazel Park High School, MI
 - **GPA:** 3.75
 - **National Honors Society Member**

Skills

Hardware/Embedded Platforms

Microcontroller:

Arduino, TMS 570

GPU/Microprocessor:

Raspberry Pi

Software Process Experience

Process Models:

Waterfall, Rapid Prototyping, Agile (Scrum, Extreme Programming, etc.)

Structural UML Diagrams:

Class, Component, Deployment

Behavioral UML Diagrams:

Activity, Sequence, Use Case, State-Transition, Communication

Industrial Exposure:

Scheduling/Tracking Performance Milestones, Understanding of Ordering Processes, Creation of Purchase Orders/Quotes

Personal Info

Email: ksbean@umich.edu Phone: (248) 808-1437 **Graduation Date:** April, 2018 Website: https://ksbean.github.io/

Key Skills

Website Design Testing (HIL environment) **Customer Interaction Technical Writing Experience**

Language Experience

C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Python, Scheme, Prolog, Lisp, Visual Basic, Assembly, HTML5, XML, CSS3

Interests and Passion

Created and currently maintain personal website. Currently working on home

automation using raspberry pi and AIY voice kit.

Wish to learn more about server side and backend website programming.



IDE Familiarity

Visual Studio 2017, Aptana, Eclipse, XAMPP, Atom

Automotive Specific dSpace, CarSim, Matlab/Simulink, Vector CANape, Vehicle Network Toolbox, IPE motion

3-D Modeling Maya, Unity, OpenGL

- Other Knowledge
 - Windows Office Enterprise: Word, Excel, SharePoint, PowerPoint, etc.
 - **Testing Processes for Industry Standards:** ISO 9000 and CMMI
 - Design and Architecture: Modern Database Architecture, Software Design/Architectural Patterns
 - Comprehension of Modern Brake Systems: Hydraulics, Sensor reading, Development of Algorithm